clickcompare.co.uk 2011-08-29

# Click Compare - The UK's largest brokerage

The Data Protection Act requires us to tell you how we collect and use data about you. You have the right to see the personal data we hold about you and change any incorrect information.

We collect personal information about you from different sources including the details you provide through this website and over the telephone. This information will be needed to provide you with the service you have requested. When dealing with your request we may contact you by post, telephone, email and SMS text.

We may need to disclose your personal information to third parties such as other members of the Tuscarora Group, other brokers, insurance companies and lenders in order to process any policy or loan you require. We may also provide your personal details to regulatory bodies if legally required to do so.

Unless you ask otherwise, we will retain your details and may also send you emails about products and services that we can offer. We will always give you the choice of whether to opt out of these emails.

By agreeing to our Privacy Policy we may, from time to time, release your details to third parties for marketing purposes of products or services that you may be interested in. We will always act to ensure that if you do not wish to receive third party information your details are removed from our database. If you would prefer not to be contacted by third parties please email us at remove@click.co.uk.

If you have applied for life insurance there may be some circumstances where we are unable to provide a quotation in which case we will forward your details to a carefully selected third party with the aim of providing the quotation you have requested

If you have applied for a loan we will use the information you have provided to:

* process the application you have made; make, or cause searches to be made, at a credit reference agency, or agencies - these searches will be shown in any other searches which are made in connection with applications made by yourself and other members of your household. The disclosure of multiple searches may adversely affect your credit profile and may make credit harder for you to obtain; information held about you by a credit reference agency may already be linked to records relating to another person, for example your spouse, and for the purpose of your loan application you will be treated as financially linked. Your loan application will be assessed with reference to all linked records;  
* if you have confirmed you are linked financially with another person, you are declaring that you are entitled to (a) disclose information about that person and/or anyone else referred to by you and (b) that you authorise the broker and any lender involved in the application to search, link and/or record information at credit reference agencies about you and/or anyone else referred to by you.

**Cookies and Web beacons**

Cookies are data files that a Web site sends to your computer while you are viewing the site. These data files include information that allows this site to remember important information that will make your use of the site more efficient and useful to you. Click's sites use cookies for a variety of purposes. We use cookie technology and IP addresses to obtain non-personal information from on-line visitors, and also to provide registered visitors with the best possible personalized on-line experience.

**How do we use cookies?**

Visitors to Click's sites use different web browsers and different computers. To make your visits as easy as possible with the technology you use, we automatically keep track of the type of browser (e.g., Internet Explorer, Netscape, FireFox, Safari and Opera) and operating system (e.g., Windows, Macintosh) used by a visitor, and the domain name of the visitor's Internet service provider. We also track the total number of visitors to this site in an aggregate form to allow us to update and improve this site; personally identifiable information is not extracted in this process. This data tells us if more visitors prefer certain features or areas to others, which helps us keep this site fresh and interesting to the majority of visitors.

**How do we use cookies to personalize your experience at Click's sites?**

Cookie technology helps us deliver content tailored to a visitor's interests, and allows us to make ordering products, entering and participating in sweepstakes and contests, and offering other functions at this site easier for visitors. Sites that offer online shopping use cookies to remember and process the items in your shopping cart. Where permitted, we may associate personal information with a cookie file in such instances.

**What if I don't want cookies?**

If you don't want cookies, you can set your computer to warn you each time a cookie is being sent or turn off all cookies through your browser (e.g., Internet Explorer, Netscape, FireFox, Safari or Opera). (Check your browser HELP menu to learn the correct way to change or update your cookies.) If you disable cookies, you may be unable to access some of the features noted above.

**What are Web beacons and how do you use them?**

Some of Click's Web pages and e-mail updates may contain electronic images called Web beacons, sometimes known as one pixel GIFs, clear GIFs or pixel tags. On Web sites, these allow us to count visitors who have viewed web pages. In promotional e-mail messages/newsletters they allow us to count how many subscribers have read them. Web beacons allow us to develop statistical information about the activities and features that most interest consumers for the purpose of providing more personalized content. They are not used to access personally identifiable information without your consent

When you use this website, you agree to us collecting and using information as we have described.

Telephone calls may be monitored and/or recorded.
